Inventory of the World Without War Council records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Financial records, 1981-1994 (Box 241-242)
- Chronological file, 1995-1996 (Box 243)
- WWWC programs (Box 243)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy (Box 243)
  - International Conflict and American Organizations (Box 243)
  - Voluntary Organizations (Box 243)
  - Peace Ballot and Peace Platform (Box 243)
- Conference, "Conscience, War and the Draft,", 1972 (Box 243)
- Circulars and bulk mailing material, 1985-1988 (Box 244)
- Research files, crises areas, Bosnia, Nicaragua (Box 245)
- Non-violence education files and questionnaires, circa 1960-1969 (Box 246)
- Course files (Box 247)
  Includes Turn Toward Peace seminars, and courses for Oregon Educational Television and religious organizations
- Funding, program files, and clippings, 1994-1999 (Box 248)
- WWWC Berkeley Fellows, 1991-1992 (Box 249)
- James Madison Foundation (Box 250)
- Speeches and writings, George Weigel (Box 250)
- Project South Africa, research (Box 251)
- World Education Center (Box 252)
- National Catholic Education Association (Box 252)
- Executive Committee meetings (Box 252)
- Research file, 1960-1974 (Box 253)
- Peace studies courses, descriptions and syllabi (Box 254)
- Research file and organizations (Box 255)
  Includes materials related to terrorism, exchange networks, conflict resolution, and Gandhi's Centennial Commission
- Board of Directors, 1986-1989 (Box 256)
- Office file (Box 257)
- Peace education in Catholic schools (Box 257)
- Diocese of Oakland (Box 257)
- Financial records, 1982-1985 (Box 258)
- Vietnam materials, circa 1972 (Box 259)
- Correspondence and photocopies (Box 260)
- Berkeley Office, photocopies (Box 261)
- Financial records, 1977-1978 (Box 262)
- Chronological file, 1987-1988 (Box 262)
- The Forerunner, 1943-1945 (Box 262)
  Periodical for high school students published by the Fellowship of Reconciliation
- Programs within the Jewish community (Box 262)
- Diocese of Oakland (Box 262)
- Research file, San Francisco State University (Box 263)
- Program notebooks, 1961-1972 (Box 264)
- Correspondence, carbon copies, 1972 (Box 266)
- Photographic slides, Episcopal Diocese of California (Box 266)
- New York Office files, 1969-1981 (Box 267)
- Photocopies, 1977-1988 (Box 268)
- Fundraising file (Box 269)
- Box Removed From Collection (Box 270-273)
- Global education (Box 274)
  See also Box 278-280
- WWWC publications (Box 275-277)
- Global education (Box 278-280)
  See also Box 274
- National Council on Philanthropy, Foundation International Group, and American Philanthropy and World Affairs, 1978-1985 (Box 281)
- Robert Pickus file (Box 282-283)
- Aiding transitions to democracy (Box 284-286)
- Issues (Box 287)
- James Madison Foundation, 1992-2008 (Box 288)
- Notebooks (Box 289-290)
- Chronological file, 1973-1974 (Box 291-293)
- Good Global Governance program, 1995-2002 (Box 294-295)
- Notebooks (Box 296-297)
- Chronological file, 1979-1988 (Box 298-300)
- Fundraising (Box 301-302)
- Global education (Box 303-308)
- WWWC publications (Box 309-311)
- Intern and Fellows Program (Box 312-314)
- Correspondence (Box 315-320)
- National Association of Evangelicals, 1984-1989 (Box 321-322)
- Correspondence (Box 323)
- Notebooks (Box 324-325)
- Regional offices, Seattle and Chicago (Box 326-328)
- Mailing list and miscellaneous (Box 329-332)
- Chronological file, 1979-1984 (Box 333-335)
- North California Consultative Group and A/V materials (Box 336-338)
- Chronological file, 1975-1979 (Box 339-342)
- Numerical file (Box 343-348)
  Numbered and arranged by WWWC. Includes office files, program files, and printed matter.
- Alliance for Education in Global and International Studies (AEGIS) (Box 349-351)
- Numerical file, 1965-1980 (Box 352-354)
- Chronological file, 1970-1972 (Box 357-358)
- Film series (Box 359)
- Historians Project (Box 360-361)
- Chronological file (Box 362-367)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 362-364)
  - 1969-1972 (Box 365-367)
- Grants, 1983-1992 (Box 368)
- Numerical file (Box 369-374)
- National Council on Philanthropy, 1977-1978 (Box 375)
- Global education (Box 376-378)
- James Madison Foundation (Box 379-382)
- Chronological file, 1975-1978 (Box 383-385)
- Intern and Fellows Program (Box 386-388)
- Good Global Governance program, 1995-2002 (Box 389-391)
- Special audiences (Box 392-393)
- Office file (Box 394-398)
  - 1983-1994 (Box 394-396)
  - 1967-1970 (Box 397-398)
- Turn Toward Peace (Box 399-401)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 399)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 400-401)
- James Madison Foundation (Box 402-404)
- American Friends Service Committee, 1951-1957 (Box 405)
- Historians Project (Box 406-408)
- Conscience and War program, 1958-2008 (Box 409-410)
- Religious Leadership program (Box 411-412)
- International Conflict and American Organizations (Box 413-414)
- Office file, 1971-1974 (Box 415-416)
- Chronologial file, 1960-1988 (Box 417-421)
- Office file, 1995-2008 (Box 422-424)
- Chronological file, 1960-1969 (Box 425-428)
- Assessing the Public Effort for Peace project, 1984-1992 (Box 429-430)
- Office file, 1979-1982 (Box 431-433)
- Acts for Peace, 1958-1962 (Box 434-435)
- Office file, 1975-1978 (Box 436-437)
- Currents of Thought (Box 438-439)
- American Initiatives Project (Box 440-441)
- Turn Toward Peace, 1961-1963 (Box 442-443)
- Assessing the Public Effort for Peace project, 1984-1992 (Box 444-446)
- Board game, "World Without War Game" (Box 447)
- Box Removed From Collection (Box 448-449)
- Chronological file (Box 450-454)
  - 1960-1970 (Box 450)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 451)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 452)
  - 1975-1978 (Box 453)
  - 1978-1980 (Box 454)
- "Definitions of World Politics Which View War as a Problem to be Solved", 1981-2010, undated (Box 454)
  Includes index
- Immigrants and Citizenship Program (Box 455-456)
  Includes correspondence, financial reports, printed matter, and other documentation concerning the program Common Good: Immigrants and Citizenship
  - Diversity scholarships, 1991-1992 (Box 455)
  - Cooperating organizations, 1991-2001 (Box 455-460)
  - Donner Foundation, 1993-1998 (Box 460-461)
  - Skaggs Foundation, Tribune Foundation, and Haas Fund, 1989-2001 (Box 462)
  - S. H. Cowell Foundation (Box 463)
  - Scholars and advisors, 1992-1998 (Box 463-464)
  - Civic education and citizenship, 1992-2002 (Box 464-465)
  - Additional programs, 1994-1998 (Box 466)
- Fellows program, 1995-2006 (Box 466-467)
- Foundations (Box 457-459)
  - James Madison Foundation, 1987-2007 (Box 467)
  - Donner, Crowell, Haas, and others, 1994-2006 (Box 468-469)
- Acts for Peace, 1958-1961 (Box 470)
- American Friends Service Commitee, 1951-1956 (Box 471)
- Box Removed From Collection (Box 472-473)
- Immigrants and Citizenship Program (Box 474-475)
  - Media and schools, 1994-2005 (Box 474)
  - Board, staff, and survey, 1994-2006 (Box 474-475)
  - Correspondence and press kit, 1996 (Box 475)
- Speeches, Robert Pickus, 1978-1990 (Box 476)
- Meeting materials and mission statement, 1985-1988 (Box 476)
- Box Removed From Collection (Box 477)
- Immigrants and Citizenship Program (Box 478-479)
  - Program files, grants, corporate files, higher education files, 1992-1994 (Box 478-479)
- Board meetings, 1961-1988 (Box 480)
- Correspondence, Robert Pickus, 1951-1995 (Box 481)
- Clippings (Box 482-484)
  Arranged alphabetically by author
  - A-C (Box 482)
  - C-J (Box 483)
  - J-Z (Box 484)
- Regional offices (Box 485)
- Immigrants and Citizenship Program, chronological file, 2001-2006 (Box 486)
- Office file, 1961-1985 (Box 487)
- Board meetings (Box 488-490)
- Correspondence (Box 491-501)
  - A-B (Box 491)
  - C-D (Box 492)
  - E-F (Box 493)
  - F-H (Box 494)
  - H-K (Box 495)
  - K-L (Box 496)
  - M-P (Box 497)
  - Q-R (Box 498)
  - R-S (Box 499)
  - R (Box 500)
  - S-Z (Box 501)
- Board meetings, 1973-2007 (Box 502)
- Good Global Governance program, 1995-2002 (Box 503)
- Office file, 1983-1994 (Box 504)
- Chronological file, photocopies, 1981-1988 (Box 505)
- Office file, 1995-2002 (Box 506)
- Audiovisual materials (Box 507-508)
  - 20 1/4-inch sound tape reels (Box 507)
  - 2 1/2-inch video tape reels (Box 507)
  - 9 VHS videocassettes (Box 508)
  - 31 compact sound cassettes (Box 508)
  - 9 16mm motion picture film reels (Film shelf)
    Center for War/Peace Studies program, "Working for a World Without War"
- Financial documents, 1958-2009 (Box 509)
- Documents to consider for digitization
  Contains materials selected by a member of the organization as good candidates for digitization. Includes documents containing biographical information about Robert Pickus, as well as materials related to WWWC history, policies, programs, and goals. (Includes empty folders with headings for documents that are present elsewhere in the collection, including in the Robert Pickus File and Extending the Democratic Peace File.)
  - Index, undated (Box 510)
  - Photograph and sketch, undated (Box 510)
    Possibly a photograph of Robert Pickus
  - Letter, "My Dearest Brother Bobby,", circa 1947-1952 (Box 510)
    Includes Pickus family history
  - "An End to War," high school essay by Pickus, 1940 (Box 510)
  - Letters from Morrie Pickus and Esther concerning Army discipline, 1943 (Box 510)
  - Clipping, "Why I am Glad to be an American,", undated (Box 510)
  - "War and Peace, Great Ideas of the Western World,", circa 1952 (Box 510)
  - "Dialogue on War,", 1950 (Box 510)
  - Autobiographical note on Pickus, circa 1948 (Box 510)
  - "Speak Truth to Power," American Friends Service Committee
    - Summary, 1955 (Box 510)
    - Response of George F. Kennan, undated (Box 510)
  - Turn Toward Peace Policy Framework and "Seven Roads to a World Without War,", circa 1961 (Box 510)
    Referred to as Pickus' "epiphany"
  - "No to Joining the World Peace Council by Robert Gilmore,", 1962 (Box 510)
  - "The Non-Communist Fellow Traveler Problem" and letters, 1962, undated (Box 510)
  - American peace strategy and foreign policy, 1964, 1982 (Box 510)
  - Preface by Pickus to Neither Victims nor Executioners by Albert Camus, 1980, 2002 (Box 510)
  - "Clarifying the Council's Work: Distinctive Elements in the Council's Approach,", 2006, undated (Box 510)
  - Survey form, "Strategy of Peace,", undated (Box 510)
  - "The Methods of Nonviolent Action," Gene Sharp, undated (Box 510)
  - "Nonviolent Transitions from Dictatorship to Peace, 1975-2000" (Box 510)
  - Vietnam peace proposals, 1979 (Box 510)
  - Initiatives to end the Vietnam War, undated (Box 510)
  - Democractic peace strategy, undated (Box 510)
  - Preface to "War and Peace in Literature,", 1981 (Box 510)
  - Speech, Pickus, "After a Miserable Afternoon at the International Non-Governmental Organizations Conference on Disarmament,", 1978 (Box 510)
  - American Initiatives Project
    - Prospectus, 1981 (Box 510)
    - Memoranda, undated (Box 510)
  - Promoting representative democracy, undated (Box 510)
  - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, actionable proposals, 1981 (Box 510)
  - Pamphlet, International Human Rights Quotient, undated (Box 510)
  - National Association of Evangelicals, guildelines, 1989 (Box 510)
  - "Steady Work," WWWC report, 1979-1980 (Box 510)
  - "Improving American Competence in World Affairs,", 1981 (Box 510)
  - "New Approaches to Peace,", 1991 (Box 510)
  - "Now, Knitting Nicely,", undated (Box 510)
    Report by Pickus after surgery
  - Global governance perspectives, undated (Box 510)
  - Citizen's primer, undated (Box 510)
  - "Psychobabble and the Peace Conference," in American Purpose, 1991 (Box 510)
  - Articles from American Purpose, James Madison Foundation, 1987-1992 (Box 510)
  - Chapters from Extending the Democractic Peac e, circa 2003 (Box 510)
  - "The Learning Curve: A Dialogue Continued,", undated (Box 510)
  - Overivew of WWWC, circa 2008 (Box 510)
    Includes overview of WWWC, a list of programs and consultancies, and Pickus bibliography
- Robert Pickus file (Box 511-520)
  Documents the life and work of Robert Pickus, founder of Acts for Peace and president of the World Without War Council.
  Materials are kept in original order; however, since materials have not been arranged, some sections are out of order based on original numbering. Boxes labeled with original headings, except where clarification was needed.
  Pickus was born in 1923 in Sioux City, Iowa. During his college years, he served as a research assistant to Mortimer Alder for the Great Books of the Western World program at the University of Chicago. In 1942, he enlisted in the army, and was called to active duty in 1943, where he completed specialized training in Scandinavian languages and was placed with the Office of Strategic Services in England and Sweden. After World War II, Pickus returned to the University of Chicago, where he received a B.A. in political science. From 1947 to 1949, he was an urban cooperative organizer sponsored by the United Automobile Workers. From 1949 to 1950, he was a Fulbright Fellow, studying with Harold Laski and Karl Popper at the London School of Economics. In 1951, he hitchhiked through France, Italy, Israel, Pakistan, Iran, and India. After his travels, Pickus began work with the Quaker organization the American Friends Service Committee (AFSC). As one of his first projects for AFSC, Pickus was part of a working party to develop a Quaker alternative to violence in international conflict. That work led to the publication of "Speak Truth to Power: A Quaker Search for an Alternative to Violence." In 1958, Pickus founded Acts of Peace after writing a letter to the War Resisters League asking them to sponsor a west coast office. In 1961, Pickus had an epiphany about the conditions essential to a world without war and created the policy framework for Turn Toward Peace, the new name of his peace organization, which eventually became the World Without War Council. Pickus would spend the rest of his life working for peace organizations, including as the president of the WWWC.
  - Index to Pickus file (Box 511)
    Original indexes accessioned with collection containing lists of documents. Box numbers in index do not correspond to current box numbers.
  - Summary of correspondence from 1942 to 2006 (Box 511)
  - Biograhpical information and chronology (Box 511)
  - Family file, circa 1945-2012 (Box 511)
    Includes correspondence from Pickus family members
  - Youth (Box 512)
  - University of Chicago, undergraudate years, 1945-1999 (Box 513-514)
  - University of Chicago, graduate school and instructor years (Box 514-515)
  - Pacifism (Box 515-516)
  - Just War colleagues (Box 516-517)
  - Extending the Commandment, "Thou Shalt Not Kill" (Box 517)
  - Strategies of work and strategies of peace (Box 518)
  - Non-governmental organizations, strategies of peace (Box 518)
  - Government, work strategies and strategies of peace (Box 518)
  - Teaching instruments (Box 519)
  - Organizational engagement (Box 519)
  - Conversations (Box 519)
  - Other organizations (Box 519)
  - A national and international presence, recognition (Box 519)
  - Relation to government (Box 520)
  - Culture (Box 520)
  - Last words (Box 520)
- Documents sent to Hoover Institution Archives and miscellaneous, 1955-2011 (Box 521)
- Printed matter (Box 522-532)
  Includes pamphlets, leaflets, and periodicals
  - ACDIS (Arms Control, Disarmament, and International Security, University of Illinois) Bulletin, (9 issues), 1982-1983 (Box 522)
  - Across Frontiers, 1969, Fall; 1977, December; 1978, March; 1981, February (Box 522)
  - ACUNU (American Council for the United Nations University) Newsletter, 1981, Winter, Supplement issue; 1982, Fall, Winter (Box 522)
  - Africare, annual report, 1983 (Box 522)
  - AFS World Review, 1975: May, November (Box 522)
  - AIM (American Independent Movement), (9 issues), 1967-1968 (Box 522)
  - American Enterprise Institute Memorandum, Fall 1983 (Box 522)
  - American Freedom From Hunger Foundation, (16 issues), 1976-1977 (Box 522)
  - American Friends Service Committee Moratorium Action Bulletin, (11 issues), 1969-1970 (Box 522)
  - American Friends Service Committee Quaker Service Bulletin, 1975, Winter; 1976, Spring; 1977, Fall, Winter; 1978, Spring (2 issues) (Box 522)
  - Beyond Kyoto, 1972, March; 1973, March; 1974, March; 1982, June-August; 1983, January, March, August-November; 1984, March (Box 522)
  - Campaign Update (National Peace Academy Campaign), 1978, Fall; 1979, Summer, Fall, Winter (Box 522)
  - The Catholic Voice, 1983, September 26 and November 7 (Box 522)
  - Center Focus (Box 522)
  - Church at Work, Special Editions (3 copies), September 1974 (Box 522)
  - Coalition Close-Up, (8 issues), 1979, 1982-1983 (Box 522)
  - Coastlines, 1983-1984, Winter; 1984, Winter (Box 522)
  - Colloquy on Teaching World Affairs, 1982: March/April, May/June, September/October; 1983, September/October; 1984, March/April (Box 522)
  - Conscience and Military Tax Campaign Newsletter, Winter 1984 (Box 522)
  - Contentions (Committee for the Free World), July/August 1983 (Box 522)
  - Continuing Education in International Affairs (University of Illinois), 1978, Spring/Summer, Winter; 1979, Winter; 1980, Winter (Box 523)
  - The Conversion Planner, September/October 1980 (Box 523)
  - Coping With Conflict, Fall 1977 (Box 523)
  - The Cornerstone, 1973; 1974; 1976, Summer, Fall; 1977, Winter (Box 523)
  - The Coronicle, 1982, Spring; 1983, Spring (Box 523)
  - Council for a Liveable World, November 1971 (Box 523)
  - Creative Simplicity, January 1977 (Box 523)
  - Czechoslovak Newsletter (Council of Free Czechoslovakia), (9 issues), 1982-1983 (Box 523)
  - Daybreak, 1983, April, June, October, November (Box 523)
  - Defense and Foreign Affairs Digest, 1973, #11/12; 1974,#1 (Box 523)
  - Diaspora (Newsletter of the Fellowship of Christian Ministries), 1978, January/February, July/August (Box 523)
  - Draft Counselor's Update (Mennonite Central Committee U.S. Peace Section), 1983, August, September/October; 1984, January/February, March/April, May/June (Box 523)
  - East Bay Democratic Socialist, 1982, June, July, September (2 issues) (Box 523)
  - East West Outlook, 1982, October; 1983, February, April, July (Box 523)
  - East West Perspectives, Special Edition, undated (Box 523)
  - Ecumenical Peace Institute Communicator, Vol. 1, Nos. 1-3, 1972 (Box 523)
  - E/SA (Engage/Social Action), 1982, December; 1983, February, March, July/August, November (Box 523)
  - Ethics and Policy, (18 issues), 1974-1983 (Box 523)
  - Ethics and Public Policy Essay, Nos. 48-49, October 1983 (Box 523)
  - Ethics and Public Policy Center Newsletter, June 1983 (Box 523)
  - European Communities Newsletter, 1983, May/June, September/October (Box 523)
  - Evolution, 1982, October; 1983, January (Box 523)
  - Fas (Federation of American Scientists) Countdown, 1982, March, May/June (Box 523)
  - FCL (Friends Committee on Legislation) Newsletter, 1967, June; 1971, February-April, October-December (Box 523)
  - First Monday, 1982, April, October (Box 523)
  - Food First News, 1983, Summer, Winter (Box 523)
  - Food Policy Center News Views, Vol. 1, Nos. 1, 6, 7 (Box 523)
  - Ford Foundation Letter, (29 issues), 1972-1979, 1981-1982 (Box 523)
  - Foreign Affairs Newsletter, (30 issues), 1974-1976 (Box 524)
  - The Freeze Exchange, 1983, February, March (Box 524)
  - Freeze Forum, June 1983 (Box 524)
  - Freeze Newsletter, (10 issues), 1983-1984 (Box 524)
  - Freeze Update, April/May 1983 (Box 524)
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation Washington Newsletter, (10 issues), 1964-1966, 1968-1969 (Box 524)
  - Gentle Strength, (23 issues), 1969-1972 (Box 524)
  - Gleanings, Vol. 7, No. 3, 1983 (Box 524)
  - Global Dimensions (University of Denver), Winter 1972/1973 (Box 524)
  - Global Perspectives, 1981, June (2 issues), Fall (Box 524)
  - Heartland, 1983, January, September/October, November/December; 1984, April/May (Box 524)
  - Humanitas International, 1981, Summer, Fall, Winter; 1982, Spring, Summer, Fall; 1983, Winter (Box 524)
  - Humanities Network, (13 issues), 1976-1977, 1979-1983 (Box 524)
  - ICYE (International Christian Youth Exchange) Newsletter, Winter 1984 (Box 524)
  - IFOR (International Fellowship of Reconciliation) Report, 1982, June; 1983, February (Box 524)
  - Initiator, Winter 1982/1983 (Box 524)
  - Institute for Global Education Equity, 1983, Summer, Fall; 1984, April, Spring, June/July (Box 524)
  - Institute for World Order, Inc., Peace Education News, 1973, October, December; 1974, May (Box 524)
  - Institute for World Order, Inc., Progress Report, 1973, May; 1974, Spring (Box 525)
  - Interaction, 1973, July-November; 1982, Fall (Box 525)
  - Interchange, 1975, September; 1976, April-June, October; 1977, January-February (Box 525)
  - International Child Resource Institute, August 1983 (Box 525)
  - International Commission of Jurists, The Review, 1972, June, December; 1973, June (Box 525)
  - International Commission of Jurists Press Release (11 issues), 1973 (Box 525)
  - International Registry of World Citizens Information Bulletin, April 1974 (Box 525)
  - IPS (International Peace Academy) News Notes, 1973, December; 1974, November; 1975, December; 1976, June (Box 525)
  - IPS (Institute for Policy Studies) Transnational Link, 1975, October, November; 1976, April (Box 525)
  - Issues (U.S. Department of State), 1969, October (2 issues), December (Box 525)
  - Issues and Actions (Newsletter of Clergy and Laymen Concerned About Vietnam), (11 issues), 1969-1970 (Box 525)
  - It's About Times (Abalone Alliance Newspaper), August/September 1983 (Box 525)
  - Jewish Peace Fellowship Newsletter, January/May 1971 (Box 525)
  - Journal of World Education, (26 issues), 1972-1978 (Box 525)
  - The Key Reporter (Phi Beta Kappa), 1967, Spring, Autumn; 1968, Autumn (Box 525)
  - KI-So De P, 1974, March, April (Box 525)
  - Linkages, May 1983 (Box 525)
  - Lotus, 1970, July 1, August 1, September 1, October 1, December 15 (Box 525)
  - Macroscope (Institute for World Order), (16 issues), 1976-1981 (Box 525)
  - Main Peace Action Committee Newsletter, 1977, September/October, October/November; 1978, February/March (Box 525)
  - MUCIA (Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities) Newsletter, 1973, December; 1974, March, October; 1975, April, 1976, May (Box 525)
  - Najda Newsletter, (12 issues), 1979, 1981-1983 (Box 526)
  - The New Abolitionist, 1983, April, May (Box 526)
  - New Directions Citizen Force, 1977, May, November/December; 1978, Spring, Winter (Box 526)
  - New Internationalist, 1973, November, December; 1975, October (Box 526)
  - The New Manhattan Project Newsletter, (24 issues), 1979-1984 (Box 526)
  - New Outlook, (12 issues), 1982-1984 (Box 526)
  - The New People (The Thomas Merton Center), (16 issues), 1979, 1981, 1983-1984 (Box 526)
  - New Politics News, 1968 (Box 526)
  - New Ways, (9 issues), 1976-1977, 1979-1981 (Box 526)
  - News From a Gently Exploding Galaxy, (6 issues), undated (Box 526)
  - News of the United Nations For Chief Executives, Fall 1983 (Box 527)
  - News of the World's Children, (14 issues), 1973-1978 (Box 527)
  - No Nuke News, February 1978 (Box 527)
  - Omaha Association of Clergy and Laity for Peace Newsletter, 1973, October, November; 1974, January (Box 527)
  - One Family (Newsletter of Planetary Citizens), (7 issues), 1977-1980 (Box 527)
  - One World, 1964, May, June, July; 1973, June/July; 1978, January, August; 1979, February, July (Box 527)
  - Open Eye, Vol. 2, No. 1, 1983 (Box 527)
  - Oxfam America News, 1983, Spring, Fall; 1984, Winter (Box 527)
  - The Paper Crane, Spring 1983 (Box 527)
  - Peace (Institute for Peace, St. Louis, Mo.), Vol. 4, No. 5; 1974, September 3, October; 1975, April/May (Box 527)
  - Peace Work, 1981, September; 1982, February, May; 1983, February, May (Box 527)
  - Planet Earth, 1980, Fall; 1982, Spring (Box 527)
  - Planetary Citizen, 1973, Spring, Summer (Box 527)